♪〜
〜♪
（吹きすさぶ風の音）
（雷鳴）
（モネヴ･ザ･ゲイル）
ハッ ハッ ハッ
ハッ ハッ
（モネヴ）ん？
How long have you
been standing there?
いつから そこにいた？
I've been watching you
the entire time.
（レガート･ブルーサマーズ）
ずっと前から見ていたよ
（モネヴ）
ヘッ 気味の悪い野郎だ
You're a creepy guy.
I'm surprised you
really showed up.
しかし 驚いたぜ
本当に現れるとはな
Did you think it was
the idle talk of a drunk?
（レガート）
酔っ払いのたわ言だと
思ってたかい？
You can't blame me
if I did.
そう考えても
しかたねえだろう
When you're stuck in a cellar,
smelling gunpowder for over 20 years...
こんな地下室で20年以上も
硝煙のにおいを嗅いでると—
...you stop caring
whether talk is true.
話の真偽なんざ
どうでもよくなるのさ
So tell me.
Who am I hunting?
教えろよ
俺は誰を狩る
（雷鳴）
（モネヴ）フッフフフ
I can feel the shivers!
ゾクゾクするぜ
Now I understand why I've
been doing this all this time.
そいつなら俺が今まで
こうしてきた意味も—
分かるってもんだ
Show our Master your gratitude
for taking you in.
（レガート）
今まで飼われていた恩を
あの方に返すんだ
（強風の音）
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
いやあ 探した 探した
Hey, I found you!
I've been looking for you
for a whole week!
探しましたよ １週間
You're almost never open because
shoes aren't the only things you sell.
たまにしか
空いてないと思ったら—
靴以外に売ってるものが
あったんだねえ
Who knew?
いやあ ハッハッハッ
You like to talk.
（靴屋の主人）
あんた しゃべり好きだ
I hope you like
to talk about shoes.
それこそ靴だけで
いいんじゃないのか？
なあ… ちょっと
知りたいことがあるんだ
Hey, wait!
There's something I want to know!
I'll abide by the rules.
ルールは守る
迷惑かけないよ
I won't make any trouble.
Please check into it.
頼む  調べてくれ
（雷鳴）
（鳥たちのさえずり）
Isn't it lovely out today?
（ミリィ･トンプソン）
いい天気ですねえ
（メリル･ストライフ）
ホントに
Oh, yes.
It makes you want to sit
here forever, doesn't it?
ずっと こうしていたいような
気分になりますねえ
ホントに
Oh, yes.
It makes you want to forget
all about work, doesn't it?
仕事なんかスコポーンと
忘れちゃいたいですねえ
Not a chance.
それはいけなくてよ
Darn.
（ミリィ）はい…
（ヴァッシュ）あーあ
マヌケなくらい青い空だ
The sky is ridiculously blue.
（子どもたち）ハッハハ それ〜
（ヴァッシュ）ああ まただよ
There I go again.
It's stupid, isn't it?
笑っちゃうよな
I still keep thinking how
I'd like to show it to you...
もうかなうこともないのに
君にも見せたいなんて
まだ考えてるんだ　俺は…
...even though that's
no longer possible.
ぐわっ
（子どもＡ）
うわあ ごめんなさい
My gosh, I'm sorry!
Are you okay?
（子どもＢ）大丈夫？
（ヴァッシュ）うおおっ
（子どもＡとＢ）うわああ！
The deadly
Dodge Ball Head!
（ヴァッシュ）
必殺 ドッチボールヘッド
The simple technique of supporting
the ball with intense suction!
強力な吸引力でボールを支える
シンプルテク
Try this at home, kids!
君もやってみよう
（子どもＡとＢ）うわああ
Hey, it's Mr. Vash!
あっ ヴァッシュさん
- I'm scared!
- I'm sorry!
（子どもＡとＢ）
ごめんなさい
（ミリィ）フフフ
What is that man doing?
（メリル）もう何やってんだか
ハア…
あ…
Aren't you glad, ma'am?
（ミリィ）
よかったですね 先輩
（メリル）へっ？
That he's back to
his usual self!
いつものヴァッシュさんに戻って
な… なな
何 言ってますの！
What are you talking about?!
All right, you guys!
Join me for ice cream!
よーし お前ら
アイス つきあえ
- Are you treating?!
- Right on!
（子どもＡ）えっ おごり？
（子どもＢ）やりい！
Get six.
（ヴァッシュ）６本な
But why six?
Isn't that one too many?
どうしてですの？
１つ多くなくて？
あの子
One is for her.
（メリル）はい どうぞ
Here you go.
（少女）あ…
Won't you play with us?
一緒に遊ばないの？
あ…
Wait!
あっ 待って
（ミリィ）それ〜
Alley-oop!
（一同の楽しげな声）
（ヴァッシュ）よっ
Whoa!
ハッ ハッ
Hey, mister!
Over here!
（子どもＡ）
おにいちゃん こっち こっち
おうっ！
Right!
（ヴァッシュ）ハッ
I've found you...
（レガート）見つけたぞ
... Vash the Stampede.
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
Who are you?
（ヴァッシュ）誰だ お前は
Legato.
（レガート）レガート
Legato Bluesummers.
レガート･ブルーサマーズ
（ミリィ）ハッ
Mr. Vash...
ヴァッシュさん
（ヴァッシュ）ん？
Hum?
い… いえ なんでも
Uh, nothing!
Hey, lady! Hurry!
（子どもＢ）
おねえちゃん 早く
Coming!
あっ はーい
What was that
look on his face?
（ミリィ）何だろう
今のヴァッシュさんの表情
What are you after?
（ヴァッシュ）目的は何だ
（レガート）君の命
Your life.
フフッ 少し無理があったかな
Did I overdo that a little?
Actually, today I'm
only here as a messenger.
実は今日の僕は
ただのメッセンジャー
That's right.
I'm here to warn you.
そう 君に忠告しに来たんだ
Your life ends today.
君の命は今日…
消える
What?
（ヴァッシュ）なにっ？
Do you think I'm lying?
（レガート）
ウソだと思うかい？
（少女）ハア…
（ヴァッシュ）あ…
わあ
（ヴァッシュ）ハッ
I haven't given you
a gift yet, have I?
（レガート）
手土産が まだだったね
（ヴァッシュ）ハアッ
（少女）ウッフフフ
（レガート）フッフッフッ
Your reaction was better
than I had hoped!
期待を上回る反応だね
You're fun.
面白いよ
And to think I could kill
every man, woman, and child here...
僕がその気になれば
ここにいるすべての人間を—
まばたきするほどの時間で
壊すことができるというのに
... in the blink of an eye
if I wanted to.
（ヴァッシュ）ううっ
Don't be in so
much of a hurry.
（レガート）
そう せかさないでほしいな
You still have
a little time left.
少しだけど まだ時間がある
Or perhaps?
それとも—
I'll leave outsiders
out of it...
周りには手を
出さないでおくけど—
... would you like to draw?
抜いてみるかい？
（レガート）
フン 賢明だね
Wise choice.
Oh, I almost forgot! This is
a little going-away present.
そうそう
これは君へのせん別
It contains a lesson from me.
I'll leave it here.
僕からの教訓入り
置いとくね
Anybody!!
（靴屋のおかみさん）誰か！
What?
何だ？
ありゃ 靴屋の
おかみさんじゃないのか
That's the shoemaker's wife.
（ヴァッシュ）あっ！
（おかみさん）
ひっ ひ… 人殺しだよ
It... It's a murder!!
おいおい 落ち着けよ
- Hey, calm down.
- Who's been murdered?!
誰が殺されたって？
My husband...
亭主が…
My husband is there,
but he won't talk!!
うちの亭主がいるのに
しゃべらないんだ
ん… 何 言ってんだよ
分かるように説明しろよ
What are you talking about?
Explain it more clearly!
（ヴァッシュ）ハッ
He what?
（男性）おい
靴屋がどうしたって？
HE WON'T TALK!
He won't say a word!!
My husband!!
（おかみさん）
何もしゃべらないんだよ
亭主が… うわああん
He didn't do it!
He's innocent!!
（メリル）
彼は殺(や)ってません　無実です
Save it for the judge.
This isn't a courthouse.
（保安官）そういうことは
法廷に出て言いたまえ
ここは審議の場じゃない
Listen, we have witness testimony
that places him at the shoe store.
いいかね
靴屋に入るあいつを
目撃した証言があって—
He was also closest when
the shoemaker's body was found.
そこの主人の死体発見時に
一番そばにいたのもやつなんだ
What's more, I checked on him only
to find he's that Humanoid Typhoon.
しかも身元を調べれば—
あのヒューマノイド･
タイフーンだというじゃないか
Anyone in their right mind
would lock him up.
俺じゃなくたって
留置するぞ 普通
If I cut him loose and
he made off into the night...
そのまま逃げられて
真相が闇に消えたら—
...would you take the heat?
責任取れるのか あんたは？
This is a little going-away present.
I'll leave it here.
（レガート）君へのせん別
置いとくね
君の命は今日…
Your life ends today.
消える
What is he after?
（ヴァッシュ）
やつの目的は何だ
The $ $60,000,000,000 reward?
600億ダブドルの賞金？
No.
いや 違う
やつか？
Is it him?!
（ナイブス）
よお！ ヴァッシュ
Hey, Vash!
（ヴァッシュ）
ああ… ああっ
ああ… ううっ…
Um, Mr. Vash?
（ミリィ）
あのう ヴァッシュさん？
キャアーッ
（メリル）ううっ
W-What's wrong?
な… なんですの？
君たちか
Oh, it's you.
あれ？
Huh?
ヴァッシュさん
Mr. Vash?
I'm sorry, but will you please
stay here without a fuss tonight?
すみませんが
今日は ここで—
おとなしくしてて
くださいます？
We'll come for you tomorrow.
あした 迎えに来ますから
Thank you...
ありがとう
...but don't try too hard.
でも 無理しないでくれ
But... you haven't done anything.
そんな…
あなたは
何もしてないんですのよ
I want to be alone right now.
今は 一人でいたいんだ
Um, Mr. Vash?
あ… あの
ヴァッシュさん？
何？
Yes?
Uh, actually...
あ… いえ
...it's muffin!
なんでもないプー
What does that mean?
なんですの それ？
Absolutely muffin!
意味なんかないプー
（激しくドアが開く音）
（保安官）ああ？
来る！
Something's coming!
えっ 何？
What?
Get down!!!
伏せろー！
（発砲音）
（モネヴ）
ヘッヘヘヘ 感謝するぜ
Thanks for showing me in!
Can you hear me,
Vash the Stampede?
聞こえてるな
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
俺の名は
モネヴ･ザ･ゲイル
My name is
Monev the Gale.
I'm here to send you to
Hell as you were promised!
約束どおり貴様を
地獄にたたき落としてやる
（メリルとミリィ）
ゲホッ ゲホッ
Both of you, run!
（ヴァッシュ）
２人とも逃げろ！
What's going on?!
何事ですか？
敵が来る！
巻き添えにならないうちに
My enemy is coming!
Get out while you can!!
早く！
Hurry!!
敵って
どういうことですの？
What do you mean, enemy?
Is someone after you?!
あなたは何に関わって…
（ヴァッシュ）どわっ
（モネヴ）ヘッ たやすいぜ
That was simple.
Simple enough to make me think
I've been wasting my life.
今までの人生が
ムダに思えるくらいにな
ヘッヘヘヘ
（銃を構える音）
（メリル）
その手を放しなさい
Let go of him!
よせっ！
DON'T!
（衝撃音）
（メリル）うっ
Ma'am!
（ミリィ）先輩
てめえ うわああ
You...
（モネヴ）ヘヘヘ
Do you know just
how long 20 years is?
20年の長さってのが
どれほどのものか分かるか？
Day in, day out, nothing but training.
It was like Hell itself!
来る日も来る日も
トレーニング
まさに地獄だったぜ
But once I kill you,
those days will be over!
だが その日々も
てめえをぶっ殺して終わる
フィニッシュまで５つ
Five counts until the end!
Four!
４つ
Three!
３つ
２つ
Two!
１つ！
One!!
Why you!!
（ミリィ）このっ！
（モネヴ）どわあっ
うわっ
（男性）うわあ
フンッ 情報どおりか
It's just like I was told!
He's a complete chicken shit!
とんだチキン野郎だ
Ma'am...
Pull yourself together, ma'am!
先輩
しっかりしてください 先輩
Th...
あ…
There's something wrong...
with him.
あの人… おかしい
What?
（ミリィ）え？
Ever since this afternoon...
昼間から様子が
What?! What's happened?!
（男性Ａ）なんだ？
何が起こったんだ？
Someone attacked
the sheriff's office!
（男性Ｂ）
保安官事務所が襲われたらしい
Who, friends of that guy
they jailed earlier?!
昼間ぶち込まれたやつの
仲間が来たのか？
Run for your lives!!
Stay away from me!!
（ヴァッシュ）
逃げろ！ 俺から離れるんだ
Let me through!!
道を開けろ！
Keep the way clear
in front of and behind me!
俺の前や後ろに立つな
町を出るまで伏せてろ
Get down on the ground
until I'm out of town!!
（男性Ｃ）あ… あいつ
- It's him!
- Vash the Stampede!
（男性Ｄ）
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
I said, get down!
伏せろってのに！
（男性Ｃ）うわあ！
Sorry, grandpa!
（ヴァッシュ）
ごめんよ ジイさん
No peeking!
顔 出すな！
Does he think he can keep it up
and still get away from me?!
あの野郎
そんなんでこの俺様から
逃げきれると思ってんのか？
（ヴァッシュ）
逃げろ！ 逃げないと撃つぞ！
Run! Run, or I'll shoot!!
（不良）ヘヘッ
何 言ってやがんでえ
Yeah, whatever.
Idiots!
バカ野郎
（不良たち）うわああ
Still stopping to help people?
That does it!
また人助けか
バカにしやがって
If you want to live,
use them as a shield!
命が惜しけりゃ
人を盾にしやがれ
Don't worry, you'll
stop twitching soon!
今からぐうの音も
出なくしてやる！
Damn it!
クソッ
（人々）わああ
（ヴァッシュ）うわっ ハアッ…
Go up with this town...
この町ごと消えちまいな
...Vash the Stampede!!
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
（発砲音）
（ヴァッシュ）あ…
ああっ…
ああっ
ハアアア…
（モネヴ）ハッハッハッハッ
I did it. I did it!
やった！ やったぜ
He was nothing!
実に たあいもねえ
Is that all there was
to the legendary outlaw?!
伝説の賞金首もこの程度かよ
Now... Now I'm free!
俺は… 俺は これで自由だ
Now I can live
the way I want to live!!
これで好きに
生きることができるんだ
アッハハハ
（銃声）
（モネヴ）うおっ！
うおお ああっ
ああ…
ああっ ああ…
It's like... It's like
I'm having a nightmare...
（モネヴ）悪い…
悪い夢を見てるみてえだ
あの目…
Those eyes...
... it's like looking into
the eyes of the diablo!
まさにディアブロの目
ああ… うわあっ
He did go this way, didn't he?
確かにこの方角ですのね
Yes.
はい
あっ
Mr. Vash!
ヴァッシュさん
STAY BACK!
（ヴァッシュ）来るな！
Stay away from me.
来ちゃダメだ
That's not him...
That's not the man I know...
違う
私の知ってる
あの人とは違う
We can't let him go...
行かしちゃダメ
だって 行ったら
それっきり戻ってこない
If we do,
he'll never come back!
I don't think
we can stop him.
（ミリィ）
止められないと思います
I don't think anyone
can stop him right now.
今のヴァッシュさんを
誰も止められないと思います
（モネヴ）なんて
精密射撃をしやがるんだ
I can't believe
that sharpshooting.
Isn't he supposed to be so wimpy,
he can't kill anyone?
人殺しができない
腰抜け野郎じゃなかったのかよ
He was like the Devil himself.
He's shown what he really is...
まさに悪魔だったぜ
本性を現しやがった
...but I still
have to kill him!
だが やつを
殺(や)ることには変わらん
Wh-What do you want?
（銀行員）
なっ なんだね あんた
I need to use your safe.
Open it.
（ヴァッシュ）
金庫を借りたい　開けてくれ
I...
（銀行員）ああ いや…
（銃を構える音）
Hurry! There's no time!!
（ヴァッシュ）
急げ！ 時間がないんだ！
Two shots left.
残り２発
Damn!
クソッ
（モネヴ）ヘッヘッヘッ
I see your plan. You're going
to use the big safe as a shield.
読めたぜ
大金庫を盾にしようって腹だな
I'll smash you
into smithereens!
粉々にしてやるぜ
はっ！ たあっ！
Along with that
vault door!!
扉ごと貫かれな！
（発砲音）
なにっ！
What?!
（銃声）
You have no more bullets!
弾はもうねえだろ！
（モネヴ）うおおお
（モネヴ）
か… 隠し銃だと？
A hidden gun?!
Why didn't he use it before?
なぜ 今まで使わなかった？
He could have shot me then.
あのときにも撃てたはずだ
許さねえ
You'll pay...
You'll pay for this!
許さねえぞ！
（足音）
（モネヴ）おおっ
（ヴァッシュ）人が死んだ
People are dead.
They're dead.
死んでしまった
だから どうした！
So what?!
うわあ
うわっ　ああっ
人が死んだ
People are dead!
THEY'RE DEAD!
死んだんだ
（モネヴ）ううう…
お前が殺したんだ
You killed them!
ひえええ
You die with them!!
お前も死ねえ！
やめて… 殺さないで
Stop... Don't kill me...
お… お願いです
Please...
...don't kill me!
殺さないで
No...
イヤだ！
I don't wanna die!!
死にたくなーい！
うわああ
ああああ！
（レム）目が覚めた？
Are you awake now?
I was dreaming...
（ヴァッシュ）夢を見ていたよ
... Rem. Everything
was so horribly dry...
レム
何もかもが
ひどく渇いていてね
... even people's hearts.
そう… 人の心も
As I watched the people
who lived there from far away...
僕は遠くから—
そこで生活する人たちを
見つめながら—
... I kept wondering
why they went on living.
どうして人は
生き続けるんだろうって—
何度も思うんだ
（レム）ウッフフフ
Why are you laughing?
何 笑ってるの？
You're so serious,
even when you're dreaming.
ヴァッシュって
夢の中でも真面目なのね
そんなこと
考えてるあいだに—
You'll turn into an old man
while you're pondering like that!
すぐ おじいさんに
なっちゃうわよ
As for me, I'm excited that the ticket
I was handed at birth is blank.
私は生まれたときに
手渡された切符が—
白紙なのにドキドキしてる
Just going over all
the possibilities...
何ができるのかを
自分の胸に聞くだけで—
... is all I can do.
精いっぱいだよ
So...
... on the first evening...
... a pebble from somewhere...
... falls upon the world.
（ヴァッシュ）
精いっぱいだよ
This is all I can do!
... on the second evening...
Mr. Vash...
ヴァッシュさん
lf...
（ヴァッシュ）僕が…
If I shot him now...
僕がここで撃てば
君は本当に死んでしまう
... you really would die.
It would be wrong
to shoot him, right?!
撃っちゃダメだよね
♪〜
〜♪
Routine report,
date: July 20th...
（メリル）
７月20日(はつか)付け 定例報告書
...two days after the incident
caused by a man named Monev.
モネヴという男が
起こした事件から２日目
Tension still runs
high in the city.
町の緊張は いまだ解けていません
This incident made me realize
something all over again.
今回 私は改めて
思い知らされました
Contact with the real Vash the Stampede
makes me forget his reputation...
ふだん 彼と接していると—
どんどん希薄になっていく
認識なのですが—
... the reason he's called
'The Humanoid Typhoon. '
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードが—
“ヒューマノイド･タイフーン”と
呼ばれるゆえん
Why is it that so much trouble
falls into this man's lap?
なぜ彼のもとには
こうも大きなトラブルが—
数多く転がりこむのでしょうか